[
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "Take notes as yo`u read a judgment using our Virtual Legal Assistant and get email alerts whenever a new judgment matches your query (Query Alert Service). Try out our Premium Member Services -- Sign up today and get free trial for one month.  1. Under section 256(1) of the Income-tax Act, 1961, at t...",
        "Entities": {
            "Virtual Legal": "ORG",
            "Premium Member Services": "ORG",
            "today": "DATE",
            "one month": "DATE",
            "1.": "CARDINAL",
            "section 256(1": "LAW",
            "1961": "DATE",
            "Madras-II": "LOC",
            "Madras": "LOC",
            "Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "2": "CARDINAL",
            "65 per cent": "MONEY",
            "Appellate": "ORG",
            "the Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Tribunal": "ORG",
            "55 per cent": "MONEY",
            "the Finance Act": "LAW",
            "1968": "DATE",
            "3": "CARDINAL",
            "Section 2(6)(d": "LAW",
            "4": "CARDINAL",
            "5": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": "No key legal principles provided.",
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/623546/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": " There is no dispute that United Kingdom is one of the countries which has been notified.  The definition of 'foreign award' will show that in order to fall within that definition. the award must satisfy certain requirements.  Firstly, it must be an award on differences between persons who have lega...",
        "Entities": {
            "United Kingdom": "GPE",
            "Firstly": "ORDINAL",
            "secondly": "ORDINAL",
            "India": "GPE",
            "thirdly": "ORDINAL",
            "11th": "ORDINAL",
            "Oct. 1960": "DATE",
            "the New York Convention": "ORG",
            "State": "ORG",
            "Parliament": "ORG",
            "18": "CARDINAL",
            "Nariman": "PERSON",
            "Counsel": "ORG",
            "Indian Organic Chemicals Ltd.'s": "ORG",
            "24": "CARDINAL",
            "1961": "DATE",
            "The New York  Convention": "ORG",
            "New York": "GPE",
            "the  1961 Act": "TIME",
            "Indian Organic chemicals Ltd.'s": "ORG",
            "41:--": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "and secondly, the legal relationship must be considered as commercial under the law in force in India, and thirdly, the award must be made on or after 11th Oct. 1960 and lastly, the award must be in pursuance of an agreement in writing for arbitration to which the New York Convention applies.",
            "The definition will show that when it referred to \"legal relationship ............. considered as commercial under the law in force in India\".",
            "it was intended to give effect to the declaration in the Convention that the legal relationship must be considered as commercial under the national law of the State making the declaration and in terms of the accession of India to the New York Convention.",
            "The declaration was that the legal relationship, whether contractual or not, was to be such as is considered as commercial under the law of India.",
            "Therefore, when the Parliament used the words \"law in force in India,\" we cannot lose sight of the fact that the use of those words was intended to give effect to the concept of  'law of India' contained in the declaration of accession and to the concept 'national law of the State making a declaration.'",
            "Mr. Nariman appearing on behalf of the appellants has contended that when the definition of foreign award uses the phraseology \"considered as commercial under the law in force in India,\" it has merely to be ascertained whether a legal relationship is regarded by law as commercial or whether a legal relationship is recognised in law as commercial and, according to the learned Counsel, it was not necessary to enact any particular statute, as seems to be contemplated by the decision in Indian Organic Chemicals Ltd.'s case  which would specify or indicate what legal  relationships were to be commercial for the purposes of the 1961 Act.",
            "the contention is that if under the general law of the land, a particular relationship was considered as commercial in the normal sense of the term.",
            "Now, when the definition of foreign award  refers to \"legal relationships ............... considered  as commercial under the law in force in India:\" we cannot overlook the fact that the 1961  Act was intended to give effect to the New York Convention.",
            "The New York  Convention mad reference to the national law and the deceleration of accession to the New York convention by India made reference  to the law of  India,  Now.",
            "the words \"national law\"  or \"the law of  India\" no  doubt will  take in a particular  statute,  but these  worse Arbitration of such wide import that they will  envelope the entire body of law which are effective or operative  in India.",
            "Indeed when the statute uses the words \"law in force  in  India\"  such use of words could never have contemplated a reference to any particular law and while it may in a given case in the context refer to a law on that particular subject, generally such words  are used  when reference is made to the general body of laws  operative  in India.",
            "We have repeatedly asked  the learned Counsel for the  intervene and the respondent as to what kind of provision they contemplate which they argued that there has to be a law which deals with contractual legal relationships and declares them to be commercial.",
            "With   several kinds of transactions which may be considered as commercial on the facts of each case, it is obvious that when the parliament referred  to the legal relationships considered as commercial under the  law in force in India.",
            "it  had in mind the general body of laws with reference to which the nature of the transaction would be considered.",
            "The  nature of the relationships will depend   in the nature of the transaction and whether the nature of the  transaction is commercial or not will have  to be determined with reference generally to the law  in force in the country  inclusive of what  the learned Judge, who decided the Indian Organic chemicals Ltd.'s case  referred to as an operative legal principle  in force in India.",
            "The mean  use of the words 'under preceding  the words  \"law in force in India\"  would not, in our view, necessarily mean that you  have to find a statutory provision or a provision of law which specifically deals with the subject of particular legal relationships being commercial in  nature.",
            "The proposition laid down by the learned Judge cannot be disputed, However,  when the learned Judge  proceeding to construe the provision in S. 2 of the 1916 Act the emphasised the use of the words \"under the law in force in India\" and then observed  as follows in para 41:--"
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/15960/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "      From more than one point of view, there is, in our view, no doubt\nthat, constitutionally, Parliament can make a law under Entry 78 of List I\nread with Entry 11A of List III of the Seventh Schedule to the Constitution\ncreating a separate division as 'Commercial Division' in the High Court and\np...",
        "Entities": {
            "more than one": "CARDINAL",
            "Parliament": "ORG",
            "Entry 78 of List": "LAW",
            "Constitution": "LAW",
            "the High Court": "ORG",
            "Division Bench": "PERSON",
            "Rs.1": "CARDINAL",
            "Division": "ORG",
            "Art": "PERSON",
            "224A": "CARDINAL",
            "the Constitution of India": "ORG",
            "High Court": "ORG",
            "the 'Commercial Division'": "ORG",
            "Chapters": "NORP",
            "Commercial Division": "ORG",
            "Chapter IX": "LAW",
            "Chapter VI": "LAW",
            "Commercial Divisions": "ORG",
            "UK": "GPE",
            "USA": "GPE",
            "The Law Commission": "ORG",
            "1996": "DATE",
            "India": "GPE",
            "Commercial": "ORG",
            "chapter VII": "LAW",
            "Commercial\nCourt Guide'": "ORG",
            "the Commercial Courts": "ORG",
            "England": "GPE",
            "Commercial Court": "ORG",
            "Theobald Matthew's": "PERSON",
            "the Commercial Court": "ORG",
            "Scrutton": "PERSON",
            "'The Work of the Commercial Courts'": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "1923": "DATE",
            "1": "CARDINAL",
            "Journal": "ORG",
            "6": "CARDINAL",
            "Practice Directions": "ORG",
            "5th Ed": "PERSON",
            "1999": "DATE",
            "Admiralty and Commercial Court Guide'": "ORG",
            "Ed": "PERSON",
            "Feb. 2002": "DATE",
            "Guide": "ORG",
            "58": "CARDINAL",
            "61": "DATE",
            "62": "CARDINAL",
            "the Civil Procedure Rules": "ORG",
            "Admiralty Proceedings": "PERSON",
            "49": "CARDINAL",
            "5th": "ORDINAL",
            "the Commercial Court Guide": "ORG",
            "the Admiralty and Commercial Courts": "FAC",
            "2": "CARDINAL",
            "NUTSHELL": "ORG"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "From more than one point of view, there is, in our view, no doubt\nthat, constitutionally, Parliament can make a law under Entry 78 of List I\nread with Entry 11A of List III of the Seventh Schedule to the Constitution\ncreating a separate division as 'Commercial Division' in the High Court and\nprescribe pecuniary limits for pending and new cases of (say) Rs.1 crore or\nabove on the original side with 'fast track' procedure and also permit the\nseparate Division Bench to deal with pending appeals in the High Court,\nbelonging to the pecuniary jurisdiction of (say) Rs.1 crore (or such higher\nfigure as may be fixed by the High Court) and to enable the Chief Justice of\nthe High Court to nominate Judges of the High Court to that Division from\ntime to time.",
            "If there are Judges who have retired and have exceptional\nknowledge of commercial laws, they can be appointed in the same or any\nother High Court and nominated to the 'Commercial Division'.",
            "The Law Commission, in its 176th Report on Amendments to\nthe Indian Arbitration and Conciliation Act, 1996 proposed a 'fast-track'\nprocedure for arbitration in India, where parties opt for such a procedure.",
            "Cambridge Law Journal 6)."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/185454903/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "          This Bill as well as the Arbitration and Conciliation (Amendment) Bill, 2015 are two of the important commercial legislations brought about by the Government with a view to providing ease of doing business in India.  \n           The Law Commission of India, headed by Chief Justice A.P. Sha...",
        "Entities": {
            "the Arbitration and Conciliation (Amendment) Bill": "ORG",
            "2015": "DATE",
            "two": "CARDINAL",
            "India": "GPE",
            "The Law Commission": "ORG",
            "A.P. Shah": "PERSON",
            "253rd Report": "ORG",
            "29th January, 2015": "DATE",
            "the Law Ministry": "ORG",
            "Commercial Disputes": "ORG",
            "the year 2015-16": "DATE",
            "The Union Law Ministry": "ORG",
            "the Rajya Sabha": "ORG",
            "the Monsoon Session": "LOC",
            "the Parliamentary Standing Committee": "ORG",
            "the All-India Judicial Services": "ORG",
            "the Indian Administrative Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Foreign Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Forest Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Police Service": "ORG",
            "the Tribunals like Competition Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "National Company Law Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Security Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "the Commercial Appellate Division of the High Court": "ORG",
            "Tribunals": "PRODUCT",
            "Section 2": "LAW",
            "Law Minister": "PERSON",
            "Law": "PERSON",
            "Schedule": "PERSON",
            "Bill": "PERSON"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "The Law Commission of India, headed by Chief Justice A.P. Shah (Retd.), in its 253rd Report dated 29th January, 2015 submitted to the Law Ministry, proposed a new legislation to deal exclusively with Commercial Disputes.",
            "The Union Law Ministry introduced this Bill in the Rajya Sabha in the Monsoon Session which was referred to the Parliamentary Standing Committee.",
            "The commercial dispute has to be heard by experts with demonstrable expertise than those people having the commercial law because it is not the institution that we are creating.",
            "We have to evolve a transparent method of appointment of judges and appoint those judges having specialised knowledge in commercial law because we are in a globalised economy and specialisation in every subject is very necessary.",
            "Just like the Indian Administrative Service, Indian Foreign Service, Indian Forest Service, Indian Police Service, we can recruit the judges in commercial courts, especially, those who are having knowledge in commercial law.",
            "But if we are recruiting judges having knowledge of general law and not having specialised knowledge of commercial law, then the same situation will arise where it is not the system which would fail us but we will fail the system itself.",
            "By this method, since a large number of Tribunals are there, the cases will automatically be transferred after the coming into force of this Act and the delay which is being caused in the Tribunals like Competition Appellate Tribunal, Debt Recovery Appellate Tribunal, Intellectual Property Rights Appellate Board, Company Law Board, National Company Law Tribunal, Security Appellate Tribunal, Telecom Dispute Settlement and Appellate Tribunal, will be reduced.",
            "Law Minister is that instead of doing this, we can include all those Acts which are dealing with the commercial disputes.",
            "Law Minister that though the word ‘commercial dispute’ has already been defined, it again needs to be reviewed."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/153530730/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "      44.  With  these  objects  in  view,  the  UNCITRAL   Model   Law   on\n      International Arbitration (“the Model Law”) was adopted by the  United\n      Nations Commission on International Trade Law (UNCITRAL) on 21st June,\n      1985 at the end of the 18th Session of the  Commission.   The  ...",
        "Entities": {
            "44": "CARDINAL",
            "International Arbitration": "ORG",
            "the Model Law": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "United\n      Nations Commission on International Trade Law": "ORG",
            "21st June": "DATE",
            "1985": "DATE",
            "the end of the 18th": "DATE",
            "Resolution 40": "LAW",
            "1972": "DATE",
            "11th": "ORDINAL",
            "December": "DATE",
            "States": "GPE",
            "Model  Law": "PRODUCT",
            "Article 1(2": "LAW",
            "Model Law": "PRODUCT",
            "64": "CARDINAL",
            "the Arbitration Act": "LAW",
            "1996": "DATE",
            "Parliament": "ORG",
            "Model  Laws": "PRODUCT",
            "Arbitration  Act": "LAW",
            "India": "GPE",
            "three": "CARDINAL",
            "1940": "DATE",
            "1937": "DATE",
            "Recognition and Enforcement) Act": "ORG",
            "1961": "DATE",
            "the Law Commission of India": "ORG",
            "Paragraph 3": "DATE",
            "Model\n      Law and Rules": "LAW",
            "3(5": "CARDINAL",
            "one": "CARDINAL",
            "66": "CARDINAL",
            "the Arbitration  Act": "LAW",
            "Arbitration Act": "LAW",
            "The Arbitration (Protocol and Convention": "ORG",
            "the Foreign Awards": "ORG",
            "Section 85": "LAW",
            "Earlier the 1937 Act": "TIME",
            "the Geneva Convention": "LAW",
            "1958": "DATE",
            "New  York\n      Convention": "GPE",
            "the Arbitration Act, 1996": "LAW",
            "Model Laws": "PRODUCT",
            "the New York Convention": "ORG"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "With  these  objects  in  view,  the  UNCITRAL   Model   Law   on\n      International Arbitration (“the Model Law”) was adopted by the  United\n      Nations Commission on International Trade Law (UNCITRAL) on 21st June,\n      1985 at the end of the 18th Session of the  Commission.",
            "The  General\n      Assembly in its      Resolution 40 of  1972  on  11th  December,  1985\n      recommended that \"all States give due consideration to the  Model  Law\n      on international commercial arbitration, in view of  the  desirability\n      of uniformity of the law of arbitral procedures and the specific needs\n      of international commercial arbitration practice\".",
            "Does the missing ‘only’ indicate a deviation from Article 1(2) of  the\n      Model Law?\n       64.",
            "As noticed earlier the objects and reasons for  the  enactment  of\n      the Arbitration Act, 1996 clearly indicate  that  the  Parliament  had\n      taken into account the UNCITRAL Model  Laws.",
            "The  statement  of  the\n      objects and reasons of the Arbitration  Act,  1996  clearly  indicates\n      that law of arbitration in India at  the  time  of  enactment  of  the\n      Arbitration  Act,  1996,  was   substantially   contained   in   three\n      enactments,  namely,  The  Arbitration  Act,  1940;  The   Arbitration\n      (Protocol  and  Convention)  Act,  1937   and   The   Foreign   Awards\n      (Recognition and Enforcement) Act, 1961.",
            "It is  specifically  observed\n      that it is widely felt that the Arbitration Act, 1940, which  contains\n      the general law of arbitration, has become outdated.",
            "It also mentions\n      that the Law Commission of India,  several  representative  bodies  of\n      trade and industry and experts  in  the  fields  of  arbitration  have\n      proposed amendments to the Arbitration Act,  1940,  to  make  it  more\n      responsive to contemporary requirements.",
            "It was also recognized  that\n      the economic reforms initiated by India at that time  may  not  become\n      fully effective, if the law dealing with settlement of  both  domestic\n      and international commercial dispute remained out of  tune  with  such\n      reforms.",
            "The objects and reasons  further  make  it  clear  that  the\n      general  assembly  has  recommended  that  all  countries   give   due\n      consideration to the Model Law adopted in 1985, by  the  UNCITRAL,  in\n      view of  the  desirability  of  uniformity  of  the  law  of  arbitral\n      procedures  and  the  specific  needs  of   international   commercial\n      arbitration practice.",
            "Paragraph 3 of the statement  of  objects  and\n      reasons makes it clear that  although  the  UNCITRAL  Model  Laws  are\n      intended  to  deal  with  international  commercial  arbitration   and\n      conciliation, they could, with appropriate modifications, serve  as  a\n      Model Law for legislation of domestic  arbitration  and  conciliation.",
            "Therefore, the bill was introduced seeking to  consolidate  and  amend\n      the law relating to  domestic  arbitration,  international  commercial\n      arbitration, enforcement of foreign arbitral award and to  define  the\n      law relating to conciliation, taking into account the  UNCITRAL  Model\n      Law and Rules.",
            "Whilst interpreting the provisions of the Arbitration  Act,  1996,\n      it is necessary to remember that we are dealing  with  the  Act  which\n      seeks  to  consolidate  and  amend  the  law  relating   to   domestic\n      arbitration, international commercial arbitration and  enforcement  of\n      foreign arbitral awards.",
            "The aforesaid Act also seeks to  define  the\n      law relating to conciliation and for matters  connected  therewith  or\n      incidental thereto.",
            "The\n      domestic  law  of  arbitration  had  remained   static   since   1940.",
            "Therefore, the Arbitration Act, 1996 consolidates the law on  domestic\n      arbitrations by incorporating the provisions to  expressly  deal  with\n      the domestic as  well  as  international  commercial  arbitration;  by\n      taking into account the 1985 UNCITRAL Model Laws.",
            "It is also necessary to  appreciate  that\n      the Arbitration Act, 1996 seeks to remove the anomalies  that  existed\n      in the Arbitration Act, 1940 by introducing provisions  based  on  the\n      UNCITRAL  Model  Laws,  which  deals  with  international   commercial\n      arbitrations and also extends it to commercial domestic  arbitrations.",
            "UNCITRAL  Model  Law  has  unequivocally  accepted   the   territorial\n      principle."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/173015163/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "47.     The   Preamble   of   the   Arbitration   and   Conciliation   Act,   1996   is   as \n\n\nfollows:\n \n...",
        "Entities": {
            "47": "CARDINAL",
            "Arbitration": "EVENT",
            "1996": "DATE"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": "No key legal principles provided.",
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/1851595/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "14.   In view of the definition of `goods' it became vital to correctly\nunderstand the nature and attributes of moveable property. The Sales\nTax Acts had no definition of the expression and the meaning given\nin the General Clauses Acts of the three States was also found to be\nnot of much help. The c...",
        "Entities": {
            "14": "CARDINAL",
            "the General Clauses Acts": "ORG",
            "three": "CARDINAL",
            "States": "GPE",
            "Black's Law Dictionary": "LAW",
            "6th": "ORDINAL",
            "1990": "DATE",
            "A.H. Hudson": "PERSON",
            "Butterworths": "PERSON",
            "1983": "DATE",
            "Jowitt": "ORG",
            "Dictionary of English Law (Sweet": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "Maxwell Limited": "ORG",
            "1977": "DATE",
            "Chapter 13": "LAW",
            "The Law of Property": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "Salmond": "PERSON",
            "Jurisprudence": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "23": "CARDINAL",
            "Anjar": "GPE",
            "Court": "ORG",
            "35": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "It referred to\nBlack's Law Dictionary (6th.",
            "Edn. 1990), Dictionary of Commercial\nLaw by A.H. Hudson (published by Butterworths, 1983) and Jowitt's\nDictionary of English Law (Sweet and Maxwell Limited, 1977) and\nnoted that all the commentaries and the referred case law uniformly\nemphasised the expansive manner in which the expression `property'\nwas understood.",
            "The court also referred to the meanings of the term\n`property' set out in Chapter 13, \"The Law of Property\" in Salmond's\nJurisprudence (12th."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/929151/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "\n 9.    The general principle that we have accepted is supported by two passages\n\nin Comparative International Commercial Arbitration.2 In paragraph 24-3\n\nthereof reference is made to Article 31(1) of the United Nations Commission on\n\nInternational Trade Law (or UNCITRAL) Rules to suggest that while...",
        "Entities": {
            "9": "CARDINAL",
            "two": "CARDINAL",
            "Comparative International Commercial": "EVENT",
            "24-3": "CARDINAL",
            "Article 31(1": "LAW",
            "the United Nations Commission on\n\nInternational Trade Law": "ORG",
            "Chapter 24": "LAW",
            "Loukas A. Mistelis": "PERSON",
            "al.": "GPE",
            "Comparative International Commercial Arbitration": "ORG",
            "Kluwer Law International": "ORG",
            "Kluwer\nLaw International 2003": "ORG",
            "627 - 662": "CARDINAL",
            "C.A. Nos.2562": "ORG",
            "2006": "DATE",
            "6": "CARDINAL",
            "24-13": "DATE",
            "11": "CARDINAL",
            "Paragraph 1353": "DATE",
            "28": "CARDINAL",
            "second": "ORDINAL",
            "Section 34": "LAW",
            "the A&C Act": "LAW",
            "Page 17": "FAC",
            "16": "CARDINAL",
            "Article 34(1": "LAW"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "In paragraph 24-3\n\nthereof reference is made to Article 31(1) of the United Nations Commission on\n\nInternational Trade Law (or UNCITRAL) Rules to suggest that while all awards\n\nare decisions of the arbitral tribunal, all decisions of the arbitral tribunal are not\n\nawards.",
            "The distinction between an award and a decision of an arbitral\n\n\n2 Chapter 24 Arbitration Award in Julian D. M. Lew, Loukas A. Mistelis, et al.,\nComparative International Commercial Arbitration, (© Kluwer Law International; Kluwer\nLaw International 2003) pp.",
            "In this context, the view\n\nexpressed in the Analytical Commentary On Draft Text of A Model Law on\n\nInternational Commercial Arbitration - Report of the Secretary-General 16 is\n\nquite relevant.",
            "This commentary deals, inter alia, with Article 34(1) of the Model\n\nLaw on International Commercial Arbitration17 and it is stated as follows:"
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/114255072/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "     (ii) in the case of international commercial\n           arbitration, the High Court in exercise of its\n           ordinary original civil jurisdiction, having\n           jurisdiction to decide the questions forming the\n           subject matter of the arbitration if the same\n           had been...",
        "Entities": {
            "the High Court": "ORG",
            "High Court": "ORG",
            "India": "GPE",
            "at least one": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "(ii) in the case of international commercial\n           arbitration, the High Court in exercise of its\n           ordinary original civil jurisdiction, having\n           jurisdiction to decide the questions forming the\n           subject matter of the arbitration if the same\n           had been the subject matter of a suit, and in\n           other cases, a High Court having jurisdiction\n           to hear appeals from decrees of courts\n           subordinate to that High Court;\n (f) “international commercial arbitration” means an\n     arbitration relating to disputes arising out of legal\n     relationships, whether contractual or not, considered\n     as commercial under the law in force in India and\n     where at least one of the parties is—"
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/79928496/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "Take notes as you read a judgment using our Virtual Legal Assistant and get email alerts whenever a new judgment matches your query (Query Alert Service). Try out our Premium Member Services -- Sign up today and get free trial for one month.  1. Under section 256(1) of the Income-tax Act, 1961, at t...",
        "Entities": {
            "Virtual Legal": "ORG",
            "Premium Member Services": "ORG",
            "today": "DATE",
            "one month": "DATE",
            "1.": "CARDINAL",
            "section 256(1": "LAW",
            "1961": "DATE",
            "Madras-II": "LOC",
            "Madras": "LOC",
            "Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "2": "CARDINAL",
            "65 per cent": "MONEY",
            "Appellate": "ORG",
            "the Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Tribunal": "ORG",
            "55 per cent": "MONEY",
            "the Finance Act": "LAW",
            "1968": "DATE",
            "3": "CARDINAL",
            "Section 2(6)(d": "LAW",
            "4": "CARDINAL",
            "5": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": "No key legal principles provided.",
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/623546/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": " There is no dispute that United Kingdom is one of the countries which has been notified.  The definition of 'foreign award' will show that in order to fall within that definition. the award must satisfy certain requirements.  Firstly, it must be an award on differences between persons who have lega...",
        "Entities": {
            "United Kingdom": "GPE",
            "Firstly": "ORDINAL",
            "secondly": "ORDINAL",
            "India": "GPE",
            "thirdly": "ORDINAL",
            "11th": "ORDINAL",
            "Oct. 1960": "DATE",
            "the New York Convention": "ORG",
            "State": "ORG",
            "Parliament": "ORG",
            "18": "CARDINAL",
            "Nariman": "PERSON",
            "Counsel": "ORG",
            "Indian Organic Chemicals Ltd.'s": "ORG",
            "24": "CARDINAL",
            "1961": "DATE",
            "The New York  Convention": "ORG",
            "New York": "GPE",
            "the  1961 Act": "TIME",
            "Indian Organic chemicals Ltd.'s": "ORG",
            "41:--": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "and secondly, the legal relationship must be considered as commercial under the law in force in India, and thirdly, the award must be made on or after 11th Oct. 1960 and lastly, the award must be in pursuance of an agreement in writing for arbitration to which the New York Convention applies.",
            "The definition will show that when it referred to \"legal relationship ............. considered as commercial under the law in force in India\".",
            "it was intended to give effect to the declaration in the Convention that the legal relationship must be considered as commercial under the national law of the State making the declaration and in terms of the accession of India to the New York Convention.",
            "The declaration was that the legal relationship, whether contractual or not, was to be such as is considered as commercial under the law of India.",
            "Therefore, when the Parliament used the words \"law in force in India,\" we cannot lose sight of the fact that the use of those words was intended to give effect to the concept of  'law of India' contained in the declaration of accession and to the concept 'national law of the State making a declaration.'",
            "Mr. Nariman appearing on behalf of the appellants has contended that when the definition of foreign award uses the phraseology \"considered as commercial under the law in force in India,\" it has merely to be ascertained whether a legal relationship is regarded by law as commercial or whether a legal relationship is recognised in law as commercial and, according to the learned Counsel, it was not necessary to enact any particular statute, as seems to be contemplated by the decision in Indian Organic Chemicals Ltd.'s case  which would specify or indicate what legal  relationships were to be commercial for the purposes of the 1961 Act.",
            "the contention is that if under the general law of the land, a particular relationship was considered as commercial in the normal sense of the term.",
            "Now, when the definition of foreign award  refers to \"legal relationships ............... considered  as commercial under the law in force in India:\" we cannot overlook the fact that the 1961  Act was intended to give effect to the New York Convention.",
            "The New York  Convention mad reference to the national law and the deceleration of accession to the New York convention by India made reference  to the law of  India,  Now.",
            "the words \"national law\"  or \"the law of  India\" no  doubt will  take in a particular  statute,  but these  worse Arbitration of such wide import that they will  envelope the entire body of law which are effective or operative  in India.",
            "Indeed when the statute uses the words \"law in force  in  India\"  such use of words could never have contemplated a reference to any particular law and while it may in a given case in the context refer to a law on that particular subject, generally such words  are used  when reference is made to the general body of laws  operative  in India.",
            "We have repeatedly asked  the learned Counsel for the  intervene and the respondent as to what kind of provision they contemplate which they argued that there has to be a law which deals with contractual legal relationships and declares them to be commercial.",
            "With   several kinds of transactions which may be considered as commercial on the facts of each case, it is obvious that when the parliament referred  to the legal relationships considered as commercial under the  law in force in India.",
            "it  had in mind the general body of laws with reference to which the nature of the transaction would be considered.",
            "The  nature of the relationships will depend   in the nature of the transaction and whether the nature of the  transaction is commercial or not will have  to be determined with reference generally to the law  in force in the country  inclusive of what  the learned Judge, who decided the Indian Organic chemicals Ltd.'s case  referred to as an operative legal principle  in force in India.",
            "The mean  use of the words 'under preceding  the words  \"law in force in India\"  would not, in our view, necessarily mean that you  have to find a statutory provision or a provision of law which specifically deals with the subject of particular legal relationships being commercial in  nature.",
            "The proposition laid down by the learned Judge cannot be disputed, However,  when the learned Judge  proceeding to construe the provision in S. 2 of the 1916 Act the emphasised the use of the words \"under the law in force in India\" and then observed  as follows in para 41:--"
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/15960/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "      From more than one point of view, there is, in our view, no doubt\nthat, constitutionally, Parliament can make a law under Entry 78 of List I\nread with Entry 11A of List III of the Seventh Schedule to the Constitution\ncreating a separate division as 'Commercial Division' in the High Court and\np...",
        "Entities": {
            "more than one": "CARDINAL",
            "Parliament": "ORG",
            "Entry 78 of List": "LAW",
            "Constitution": "LAW",
            "the High Court": "ORG",
            "Division Bench": "PERSON",
            "Rs.1": "CARDINAL",
            "Division": "ORG",
            "Art": "PERSON",
            "224A": "CARDINAL",
            "the Constitution of India": "ORG",
            "High Court": "ORG",
            "the 'Commercial Division'": "ORG",
            "Chapters": "NORP",
            "Commercial Division": "ORG",
            "Chapter IX": "LAW",
            "Chapter VI": "LAW",
            "Commercial Divisions": "ORG",
            "UK": "GPE",
            "USA": "GPE",
            "The Law Commission": "ORG",
            "1996": "DATE",
            "India": "GPE",
            "Commercial": "ORG",
            "chapter VII": "LAW",
            "Commercial\nCourt Guide'": "ORG",
            "the Commercial Courts": "ORG",
            "England": "GPE",
            "Commercial Court": "ORG",
            "Theobald Matthew's": "PERSON",
            "the Commercial Court": "ORG",
            "Scrutton": "PERSON",
            "'The Work of the Commercial Courts'": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "1923": "DATE",
            "1": "CARDINAL",
            "Journal": "ORG",
            "6": "CARDINAL",
            "Practice Directions": "ORG",
            "5th Ed": "PERSON",
            "1999": "DATE",
            "Admiralty and Commercial Court Guide'": "ORG",
            "Ed": "PERSON",
            "Feb. 2002": "DATE",
            "Guide": "ORG",
            "58": "CARDINAL",
            "61": "DATE",
            "62": "CARDINAL",
            "the Civil Procedure Rules": "ORG",
            "Admiralty Proceedings": "PERSON",
            "49": "CARDINAL",
            "5th": "ORDINAL",
            "the Commercial Court Guide": "ORG",
            "the Admiralty and Commercial Courts": "FAC",
            "2": "CARDINAL",
            "NUTSHELL": "ORG"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "From more than one point of view, there is, in our view, no doubt\nthat, constitutionally, Parliament can make a law under Entry 78 of List I\nread with Entry 11A of List III of the Seventh Schedule to the Constitution\ncreating a separate division as 'Commercial Division' in the High Court and\nprescribe pecuniary limits for pending and new cases of (say) Rs.1 crore or\nabove on the original side with 'fast track' procedure and also permit the\nseparate Division Bench to deal with pending appeals in the High Court,\nbelonging to the pecuniary jurisdiction of (say) Rs.1 crore (or such higher\nfigure as may be fixed by the High Court) and to enable the Chief Justice of\nthe High Court to nominate Judges of the High Court to that Division from\ntime to time.",
            "If there are Judges who have retired and have exceptional\nknowledge of commercial laws, they can be appointed in the same or any\nother High Court and nominated to the 'Commercial Division'.",
            "The Law Commission, in its 176th Report on Amendments to\nthe Indian Arbitration and Conciliation Act, 1996 proposed a 'fast-track'\nprocedure for arbitration in India, where parties opt for such a procedure.",
            "Cambridge Law Journal 6)."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/185454903/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "          This Bill as well as the Arbitration and Conciliation (Amendment) Bill, 2015 are two of the important commercial legislations brought about by the Government with a view to providing ease of doing business in India.  \n           The Law Commission of India, headed by Chief Justice A.P. Sha...",
        "Entities": {
            "the Arbitration and Conciliation (Amendment) Bill": "ORG",
            "2015": "DATE",
            "two": "CARDINAL",
            "India": "GPE",
            "The Law Commission": "ORG",
            "A.P. Shah": "PERSON",
            "253rd Report": "ORG",
            "29th January, 2015": "DATE",
            "the Law Ministry": "ORG",
            "Commercial Disputes": "ORG",
            "the year 2015-16": "DATE",
            "The Union Law Ministry": "ORG",
            "the Rajya Sabha": "ORG",
            "the Monsoon Session": "LOC",
            "the Parliamentary Standing Committee": "ORG",
            "the All-India Judicial Services": "ORG",
            "the Indian Administrative Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Foreign Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Forest Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Police Service": "ORG",
            "the Tribunals like Competition Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "National Company Law Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Security Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "the Commercial Appellate Division of the High Court": "ORG",
            "Tribunals": "PRODUCT",
            "Section 2": "LAW",
            "Law Minister": "PERSON",
            "Law": "PERSON",
            "Schedule": "PERSON",
            "Bill": "PERSON"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "The Law Commission of India, headed by Chief Justice A.P. Shah (Retd.), in its 253rd Report dated 29th January, 2015 submitted to the Law Ministry, proposed a new legislation to deal exclusively with Commercial Disputes.",
            "The Union Law Ministry introduced this Bill in the Rajya Sabha in the Monsoon Session which was referred to the Parliamentary Standing Committee.",
            "The commercial dispute has to be heard by experts with demonstrable expertise than those people having the commercial law because it is not the institution that we are creating.",
            "We have to evolve a transparent method of appointment of judges and appoint those judges having specialised knowledge in commercial law because we are in a globalised economy and specialisation in every subject is very necessary.",
            "Just like the Indian Administrative Service, Indian Foreign Service, Indian Forest Service, Indian Police Service, we can recruit the judges in commercial courts, especially, those who are having knowledge in commercial law.",
            "But if we are recruiting judges having knowledge of general law and not having specialised knowledge of commercial law, then the same situation will arise where it is not the system which would fail us but we will fail the system itself.",
            "By this method, since a large number of Tribunals are there, the cases will automatically be transferred after the coming into force of this Act and the delay which is being caused in the Tribunals like Competition Appellate Tribunal, Debt Recovery Appellate Tribunal, Intellectual Property Rights Appellate Board, Company Law Board, National Company Law Tribunal, Security Appellate Tribunal, Telecom Dispute Settlement and Appellate Tribunal, will be reduced.",
            "Law Minister is that instead of doing this, we can include all those Acts which are dealing with the commercial disputes.",
            "Law Minister that though the word ‘commercial dispute’ has already been defined, it again needs to be reviewed."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/153530730/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "      44.  With  these  objects  in  view,  the  UNCITRAL   Model   Law   on\n      International Arbitration (“the Model Law”) was adopted by the  United\n      Nations Commission on International Trade Law (UNCITRAL) on 21st June,\n      1985 at the end of the 18th Session of the  Commission.   The  ...",
        "Entities": {
            "44": "CARDINAL",
            "International Arbitration": "ORG",
            "the Model Law": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "United\n      Nations Commission on International Trade Law": "ORG",
            "21st June": "DATE",
            "1985": "DATE",
            "the end of the 18th": "DATE",
            "Resolution 40": "LAW",
            "1972": "DATE",
            "11th": "ORDINAL",
            "December": "DATE",
            "States": "GPE",
            "Model  Law": "PRODUCT",
            "Article 1(2": "LAW",
            "Model Law": "PRODUCT",
            "64": "CARDINAL",
            "the Arbitration Act": "LAW",
            "1996": "DATE",
            "Parliament": "ORG",
            "Model  Laws": "PRODUCT",
            "Arbitration  Act": "LAW",
            "India": "GPE",
            "three": "CARDINAL",
            "1940": "DATE",
            "1937": "DATE",
            "Recognition and Enforcement) Act": "ORG",
            "1961": "DATE",
            "the Law Commission of India": "ORG",
            "Paragraph 3": "DATE",
            "Model\n      Law and Rules": "LAW",
            "3(5": "CARDINAL",
            "one": "CARDINAL",
            "66": "CARDINAL",
            "the Arbitration  Act": "LAW",
            "Arbitration Act": "LAW",
            "The Arbitration (Protocol and Convention": "ORG",
            "the Foreign Awards": "ORG",
            "Section 85": "LAW",
            "Earlier the 1937 Act": "TIME",
            "the Geneva Convention": "LAW",
            "1958": "DATE",
            "New  York\n      Convention": "GPE",
            "the Arbitration Act, 1996": "LAW",
            "Model Laws": "PRODUCT",
            "the New York Convention": "ORG"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "With  these  objects  in  view,  the  UNCITRAL   Model   Law   on\n      International Arbitration (“the Model Law”) was adopted by the  United\n      Nations Commission on International Trade Law (UNCITRAL) on 21st June,\n      1985 at the end of the 18th Session of the  Commission.",
            "The  General\n      Assembly in its      Resolution 40 of  1972  on  11th  December,  1985\n      recommended that \"all States give due consideration to the  Model  Law\n      on international commercial arbitration, in view of  the  desirability\n      of uniformity of the law of arbitral procedures and the specific needs\n      of international commercial arbitration practice\".",
            "Does the missing ‘only’ indicate a deviation from Article 1(2) of  the\n      Model Law?\n       64.",
            "As noticed earlier the objects and reasons for  the  enactment  of\n      the Arbitration Act, 1996 clearly indicate  that  the  Parliament  had\n      taken into account the UNCITRAL Model  Laws.",
            "The  statement  of  the\n      objects and reasons of the Arbitration  Act,  1996  clearly  indicates\n      that law of arbitration in India at  the  time  of  enactment  of  the\n      Arbitration  Act,  1996,  was   substantially   contained   in   three\n      enactments,  namely,  The  Arbitration  Act,  1940;  The   Arbitration\n      (Protocol  and  Convention)  Act,  1937   and   The   Foreign   Awards\n      (Recognition and Enforcement) Act, 1961.",
            "It is  specifically  observed\n      that it is widely felt that the Arbitration Act, 1940, which  contains\n      the general law of arbitration, has become outdated.",
            "It also mentions\n      that the Law Commission of India,  several  representative  bodies  of\n      trade and industry and experts  in  the  fields  of  arbitration  have\n      proposed amendments to the Arbitration Act,  1940,  to  make  it  more\n      responsive to contemporary requirements.",
            "It was also recognized  that\n      the economic reforms initiated by India at that time  may  not  become\n      fully effective, if the law dealing with settlement of  both  domestic\n      and international commercial dispute remained out of  tune  with  such\n      reforms.",
            "The objects and reasons  further  make  it  clear  that  the\n      general  assembly  has  recommended  that  all  countries   give   due\n      consideration to the Model Law adopted in 1985, by  the  UNCITRAL,  in\n      view of  the  desirability  of  uniformity  of  the  law  of  arbitral\n      procedures  and  the  specific  needs  of   international   commercial\n      arbitration practice.",
            "Paragraph 3 of the statement  of  objects  and\n      reasons makes it clear that  although  the  UNCITRAL  Model  Laws  are\n      intended  to  deal  with  international  commercial  arbitration   and\n      conciliation, they could, with appropriate modifications, serve  as  a\n      Model Law for legislation of domestic  arbitration  and  conciliation.",
            "Therefore, the bill was introduced seeking to  consolidate  and  amend\n      the law relating to  domestic  arbitration,  international  commercial\n      arbitration, enforcement of foreign arbitral award and to  define  the\n      law relating to conciliation, taking into account the  UNCITRAL  Model\n      Law and Rules.",
            "Whilst interpreting the provisions of the Arbitration  Act,  1996,\n      it is necessary to remember that we are dealing  with  the  Act  which\n      seeks  to  consolidate  and  amend  the  law  relating   to   domestic\n      arbitration, international commercial arbitration and  enforcement  of\n      foreign arbitral awards.",
            "The aforesaid Act also seeks to  define  the\n      law relating to conciliation and for matters  connected  therewith  or\n      incidental thereto.",
            "The\n      domestic  law  of  arbitration  had  remained   static   since   1940.",
            "Therefore, the Arbitration Act, 1996 consolidates the law on  domestic\n      arbitrations by incorporating the provisions to  expressly  deal  with\n      the domestic as  well  as  international  commercial  arbitration;  by\n      taking into account the 1985 UNCITRAL Model Laws.",
            "It is also necessary to  appreciate  that\n      the Arbitration Act, 1996 seeks to remove the anomalies  that  existed\n      in the Arbitration Act, 1940 by introducing provisions  based  on  the\n      UNCITRAL  Model  Laws,  which  deals  with  international   commercial\n      arbitrations and also extends it to commercial domestic  arbitrations.",
            "UNCITRAL  Model  Law  has  unequivocally  accepted   the   territorial\n      principle."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/173015163/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "47.     The   Preamble   of   the   Arbitration   and   Conciliation   Act,   1996   is   as \n\n\nfollows:\n \n...",
        "Entities": {
            "47": "CARDINAL",
            "Arbitration": "EVENT",
            "1996": "DATE"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": "No key legal principles provided.",
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/1851595/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "14.   In view of the definition of `goods' it became vital to correctly\nunderstand the nature and attributes of moveable property. The Sales\nTax Acts had no definition of the expression and the meaning given\nin the General Clauses Acts of the three States was also found to be\nnot of much help. The c...",
        "Entities": {
            "14": "CARDINAL",
            "the General Clauses Acts": "ORG",
            "three": "CARDINAL",
            "States": "GPE",
            "Black's Law Dictionary": "LAW",
            "6th": "ORDINAL",
            "1990": "DATE",
            "A.H. Hudson": "PERSON",
            "Butterworths": "PERSON",
            "1983": "DATE",
            "Jowitt": "ORG",
            "Dictionary of English Law (Sweet": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "Maxwell Limited": "ORG",
            "1977": "DATE",
            "Chapter 13": "LAW",
            "The Law of Property": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "Salmond": "PERSON",
            "Jurisprudence": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "23": "CARDINAL",
            "Anjar": "GPE",
            "Court": "ORG",
            "35": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "It referred to\nBlack's Law Dictionary (6th.",
            "Edn. 1990), Dictionary of Commercial\nLaw by A.H. Hudson (published by Butterworths, 1983) and Jowitt's\nDictionary of English Law (Sweet and Maxwell Limited, 1977) and\nnoted that all the commentaries and the referred case law uniformly\nemphasised the expansive manner in which the expression `property'\nwas understood.",
            "The court also referred to the meanings of the term\n`property' set out in Chapter 13, \"The Law of Property\" in Salmond's\nJurisprudence (12th."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/929151/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "\n 9.    The general principle that we have accepted is supported by two passages\n\nin Comparative International Commercial Arbitration.2 In paragraph 24-3\n\nthereof reference is made to Article 31(1) of the United Nations Commission on\n\nInternational Trade Law (or UNCITRAL) Rules to suggest that while...",
        "Entities": {
            "9": "CARDINAL",
            "two": "CARDINAL",
            "Comparative International Commercial": "EVENT",
            "24-3": "CARDINAL",
            "Article 31(1": "LAW",
            "the United Nations Commission on\n\nInternational Trade Law": "ORG",
            "Chapter 24": "LAW",
            "Loukas A. Mistelis": "PERSON",
            "al.": "GPE",
            "Comparative International Commercial Arbitration": "ORG",
            "Kluwer Law International": "ORG",
            "Kluwer\nLaw International 2003": "ORG",
            "627 - 662": "CARDINAL",
            "C.A. Nos.2562": "ORG",
            "2006": "DATE",
            "6": "CARDINAL",
            "24-13": "DATE",
            "11": "CARDINAL",
            "Paragraph 1353": "DATE",
            "28": "CARDINAL",
            "second": "ORDINAL",
            "Section 34": "LAW",
            "the A&C Act": "LAW",
            "Page 17": "FAC",
            "16": "CARDINAL",
            "Article 34(1": "LAW"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "In paragraph 24-3\n\nthereof reference is made to Article 31(1) of the United Nations Commission on\n\nInternational Trade Law (or UNCITRAL) Rules to suggest that while all awards\n\nare decisions of the arbitral tribunal, all decisions of the arbitral tribunal are not\n\nawards.",
            "The distinction between an award and a decision of an arbitral\n\n\n2 Chapter 24 Arbitration Award in Julian D. M. Lew, Loukas A. Mistelis, et al.,\nComparative International Commercial Arbitration, (© Kluwer Law International; Kluwer\nLaw International 2003) pp.",
            "In this context, the view\n\nexpressed in the Analytical Commentary On Draft Text of A Model Law on\n\nInternational Commercial Arbitration - Report of the Secretary-General 16 is\n\nquite relevant.",
            "This commentary deals, inter alia, with Article 34(1) of the Model\n\nLaw on International Commercial Arbitration17 and it is stated as follows:"
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/114255072/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "     (ii) in the case of international commercial\n           arbitration, the High Court in exercise of its\n           ordinary original civil jurisdiction, having\n           jurisdiction to decide the questions forming the\n           subject matter of the arbitration if the same\n           had been...",
        "Entities": {
            "the High Court": "ORG",
            "High Court": "ORG",
            "India": "GPE",
            "at least one": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "(ii) in the case of international commercial\n           arbitration, the High Court in exercise of its\n           ordinary original civil jurisdiction, having\n           jurisdiction to decide the questions forming the\n           subject matter of the arbitration if the same\n           had been the subject matter of a suit, and in\n           other cases, a High Court having jurisdiction\n           to hear appeals from decrees of courts\n           subordinate to that High Court;\n (f) “international commercial arbitration” means an\n     arbitration relating to disputes arising out of legal\n     relationships, whether contractual or not, considered\n     as commercial under the law in force in India and\n     where at least one of the parties is—"
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/79928496/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "Take notes as you read a judgment using our Virtual Legal Assistant and get email alerts whenever a new judgment matches your query (Query Alert Service). Try out our Premium Member Services -- Sign up today and get free trial for one month.  1. Under section 256(1) of the Income-tax Act, 1961, at t...",
        "Entities": {
            "Virtual Legal": "ORG",
            "Premium Member Services": "ORG",
            "today": "DATE",
            "one month": "DATE",
            "1.": "CARDINAL",
            "section 256(1": "LAW",
            "1961": "DATE",
            "Madras-II": "LOC",
            "Madras": "LOC",
            "Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "2": "CARDINAL",
            "65 per cent": "MONEY",
            "Appellate": "ORG",
            "the Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Tribunal": "ORG",
            "55 per cent": "MONEY",
            "the Finance Act": "LAW",
            "1968": "DATE",
            "3": "CARDINAL",
            "Section 2(6)(d": "LAW",
            "4": "CARDINAL",
            "5": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": "No key legal principles provided.",
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/623546/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": " There is no dispute that United Kingdom is one of the countries which has been notified.  The definition of 'foreign award' will show that in order to fall within that definition. the award must satisfy certain requirements.  Firstly, it must be an award on differences between persons who have lega...",
        "Entities": {
            "United Kingdom": "GPE",
            "Firstly": "ORDINAL",
            "secondly": "ORDINAL",
            "India": "GPE",
            "thirdly": "ORDINAL",
            "11th": "ORDINAL",
            "Oct. 1960": "DATE",
            "the New York Convention": "ORG",
            "State": "ORG",
            "Parliament": "ORG",
            "18": "CARDINAL",
            "Nariman": "PERSON",
            "Counsel": "ORG",
            "Indian Organic Chemicals Ltd.'s": "ORG",
            "24": "CARDINAL",
            "1961": "DATE",
            "The New York  Convention": "ORG",
            "New York": "GPE",
            "the  1961 Act": "TIME",
            "Indian Organic chemicals Ltd.'s": "ORG",
            "41:--": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "and secondly, the legal relationship must be considered as commercial under the law in force in India, and thirdly, the award must be made on or after 11th Oct. 1960 and lastly, the award must be in pursuance of an agreement in writing for arbitration to which the New York Convention applies.",
            "The definition will show that when it referred to \"legal relationship ............. considered as commercial under the law in force in India\".",
            "it was intended to give effect to the declaration in the Convention that the legal relationship must be considered as commercial under the national law of the State making the declaration and in terms of the accession of India to the New York Convention.",
            "The declaration was that the legal relationship, whether contractual or not, was to be such as is considered as commercial under the law of India.",
            "Therefore, when the Parliament used the words \"law in force in India,\" we cannot lose sight of the fact that the use of those words was intended to give effect to the concept of  'law of India' contained in the declaration of accession and to the concept 'national law of the State making a declaration.'",
            "Mr. Nariman appearing on behalf of the appellants has contended that when the definition of foreign award uses the phraseology \"considered as commercial under the law in force in India,\" it has merely to be ascertained whether a legal relationship is regarded by law as commercial or whether a legal relationship is recognised in law as commercial and, according to the learned Counsel, it was not necessary to enact any particular statute, as seems to be contemplated by the decision in Indian Organic Chemicals Ltd.'s case  which would specify or indicate what legal  relationships were to be commercial for the purposes of the 1961 Act.",
            "the contention is that if under the general law of the land, a particular relationship was considered as commercial in the normal sense of the term.",
            "Now, when the definition of foreign award  refers to \"legal relationships ............... considered  as commercial under the law in force in India:\" we cannot overlook the fact that the 1961  Act was intended to give effect to the New York Convention.",
            "The New York  Convention mad reference to the national law and the deceleration of accession to the New York convention by India made reference  to the law of  India,  Now.",
            "the words \"national law\"  or \"the law of  India\" no  doubt will  take in a particular  statute,  but these  worse Arbitration of such wide import that they will  envelope the entire body of law which are effective or operative  in India.",
            "Indeed when the statute uses the words \"law in force  in  India\"  such use of words could never have contemplated a reference to any particular law and while it may in a given case in the context refer to a law on that particular subject, generally such words  are used  when reference is made to the general body of laws  operative  in India.",
            "We have repeatedly asked  the learned Counsel for the  intervene and the respondent as to what kind of provision they contemplate which they argued that there has to be a law which deals with contractual legal relationships and declares them to be commercial.",
            "With   several kinds of transactions which may be considered as commercial on the facts of each case, it is obvious that when the parliament referred  to the legal relationships considered as commercial under the  law in force in India.",
            "it  had in mind the general body of laws with reference to which the nature of the transaction would be considered.",
            "The  nature of the relationships will depend   in the nature of the transaction and whether the nature of the  transaction is commercial or not will have  to be determined with reference generally to the law  in force in the country  inclusive of what  the learned Judge, who decided the Indian Organic chemicals Ltd.'s case  referred to as an operative legal principle  in force in India.",
            "The mean  use of the words 'under preceding  the words  \"law in force in India\"  would not, in our view, necessarily mean that you  have to find a statutory provision or a provision of law which specifically deals with the subject of particular legal relationships being commercial in  nature.",
            "The proposition laid down by the learned Judge cannot be disputed, However,  when the learned Judge  proceeding to construe the provision in S. 2 of the 1916 Act the emphasised the use of the words \"under the law in force in India\" and then observed  as follows in para 41:--"
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/15960/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "      From more than one point of view, there is, in our view, no doubt\nthat, constitutionally, Parliament can make a law under Entry 78 of List I\nread with Entry 11A of List III of the Seventh Schedule to the Constitution\ncreating a separate division as 'Commercial Division' in the High Court and\np...",
        "Entities": {
            "more than one": "CARDINAL",
            "Parliament": "ORG",
            "Entry 78 of List": "LAW",
            "Constitution": "LAW",
            "the High Court": "ORG",
            "Division Bench": "PERSON",
            "Rs.1": "CARDINAL",
            "Division": "ORG",
            "Art": "PERSON",
            "224A": "CARDINAL",
            "the Constitution of India": "ORG",
            "High Court": "ORG",
            "the 'Commercial Division'": "ORG",
            "Chapters": "NORP",
            "Commercial Division": "ORG",
            "Chapter IX": "LAW",
            "Chapter VI": "LAW",
            "Commercial Divisions": "ORG",
            "UK": "GPE",
            "USA": "GPE",
            "The Law Commission": "ORG",
            "1996": "DATE",
            "India": "GPE",
            "Commercial": "ORG",
            "chapter VII": "LAW",
            "Commercial\nCourt Guide'": "ORG",
            "the Commercial Courts": "ORG",
            "England": "GPE",
            "Commercial Court": "ORG",
            "Theobald Matthew's": "PERSON",
            "the Commercial Court": "ORG",
            "Scrutton": "PERSON",
            "'The Work of the Commercial Courts'": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "1923": "DATE",
            "1": "CARDINAL",
            "Journal": "ORG",
            "6": "CARDINAL",
            "Practice Directions": "ORG",
            "5th Ed": "PERSON",
            "1999": "DATE",
            "Admiralty and Commercial Court Guide'": "ORG",
            "Ed": "PERSON",
            "Feb. 2002": "DATE",
            "Guide": "ORG",
            "58": "CARDINAL",
            "61": "DATE",
            "62": "CARDINAL",
            "the Civil Procedure Rules": "ORG",
            "Admiralty Proceedings": "PERSON",
            "49": "CARDINAL",
            "5th": "ORDINAL",
            "the Commercial Court Guide": "ORG",
            "the Admiralty and Commercial Courts": "FAC",
            "2": "CARDINAL",
            "NUTSHELL": "ORG"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "From more than one point of view, there is, in our view, no doubt\nthat, constitutionally, Parliament can make a law under Entry 78 of List I\nread with Entry 11A of List III of the Seventh Schedule to the Constitution\ncreating a separate division as 'Commercial Division' in the High Court and\nprescribe pecuniary limits for pending and new cases of (say) Rs.1 crore or\nabove on the original side with 'fast track' procedure and also permit the\nseparate Division Bench to deal with pending appeals in the High Court,\nbelonging to the pecuniary jurisdiction of (say) Rs.1 crore (or such higher\nfigure as may be fixed by the High Court) and to enable the Chief Justice of\nthe High Court to nominate Judges of the High Court to that Division from\ntime to time.",
            "If there are Judges who have retired and have exceptional\nknowledge of commercial laws, they can be appointed in the same or any\nother High Court and nominated to the 'Commercial Division'.",
            "The Law Commission, in its 176th Report on Amendments to\nthe Indian Arbitration and Conciliation Act, 1996 proposed a 'fast-track'\nprocedure for arbitration in India, where parties opt for such a procedure.",
            "Cambridge Law Journal 6)."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/185454903/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "          This Bill as well as the Arbitration and Conciliation (Amendment) Bill, 2015 are two of the important commercial legislations brought about by the Government with a view to providing ease of doing business in India.  \n           The Law Commission of India, headed by Chief Justice A.P. Sha...",
        "Entities": {
            "the Arbitration and Conciliation (Amendment) Bill": "ORG",
            "2015": "DATE",
            "two": "CARDINAL",
            "India": "GPE",
            "The Law Commission": "ORG",
            "A.P. Shah": "PERSON",
            "253rd Report": "ORG",
            "29th January, 2015": "DATE",
            "the Law Ministry": "ORG",
            "Commercial Disputes": "ORG",
            "the year 2015-16": "DATE",
            "The Union Law Ministry": "ORG",
            "the Rajya Sabha": "ORG",
            "the Monsoon Session": "LOC",
            "the Parliamentary Standing Committee": "ORG",
            "the All-India Judicial Services": "ORG",
            "the Indian Administrative Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Foreign Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Forest Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Police Service": "ORG",
            "the Tribunals like Competition Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "National Company Law Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Security Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "the Commercial Appellate Division of the High Court": "ORG",
            "Tribunals": "PRODUCT",
            "Section 2": "LAW",
            "Law Minister": "PERSON",
            "Law": "PERSON",
            "Schedule": "PERSON",
            "Bill": "PERSON"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "The Law Commission of India, headed by Chief Justice A.P. Shah (Retd.), in its 253rd Report dated 29th January, 2015 submitted to the Law Ministry, proposed a new legislation to deal exclusively with Commercial Disputes.",
            "The Union Law Ministry introduced this Bill in the Rajya Sabha in the Monsoon Session which was referred to the Parliamentary Standing Committee.",
            "The commercial dispute has to be heard by experts with demonstrable expertise than those people having the commercial law because it is not the institution that we are creating.",
            "We have to evolve a transparent method of appointment of judges and appoint those judges having specialised knowledge in commercial law because we are in a globalised economy and specialisation in every subject is very necessary.",
            "Just like the Indian Administrative Service, Indian Foreign Service, Indian Forest Service, Indian Police Service, we can recruit the judges in commercial courts, especially, those who are having knowledge in commercial law.",
            "But if we are recruiting judges having knowledge of general law and not having specialised knowledge of commercial law, then the same situation will arise where it is not the system which would fail us but we will fail the system itself.",
            "By this method, since a large number of Tribunals are there, the cases will automatically be transferred after the coming into force of this Act and the delay which is being caused in the Tribunals like Competition Appellate Tribunal, Debt Recovery Appellate Tribunal, Intellectual Property Rights Appellate Board, Company Law Board, National Company Law Tribunal, Security Appellate Tribunal, Telecom Dispute Settlement and Appellate Tribunal, will be reduced.",
            "Law Minister is that instead of doing this, we can include all those Acts which are dealing with the commercial disputes.",
            "Law Minister that though the word ‘commercial dispute’ has already been defined, it again needs to be reviewed."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/153530730/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "      44.  With  these  objects  in  view,  the  UNCITRAL   Model   Law   on\n      International Arbitration (“the Model Law”) was adopted by the  United\n      Nations Commission on International Trade Law (UNCITRAL) on 21st June,\n      1985 at the end of the 18th Session of the  Commission.   The  ...",
        "Entities": {
            "44": "CARDINAL",
            "International Arbitration": "ORG",
            "the Model Law": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "United\n      Nations Commission on International Trade Law": "ORG",
            "21st June": "DATE",
            "1985": "DATE",
            "the end of the 18th": "DATE",
            "Resolution 40": "LAW",
            "1972": "DATE",
            "11th": "ORDINAL",
            "December": "DATE",
            "States": "GPE",
            "Model  Law": "PRODUCT",
            "Article 1(2": "LAW",
            "Model Law": "PRODUCT",
            "64": "CARDINAL",
            "the Arbitration Act": "LAW",
            "1996": "DATE",
            "Parliament": "ORG",
            "Model  Laws": "PRODUCT",
            "Arbitration  Act": "LAW",
            "India": "GPE",
            "three": "CARDINAL",
            "1940": "DATE",
            "1937": "DATE",
            "Recognition and Enforcement) Act": "ORG",
            "1961": "DATE",
            "the Law Commission of India": "ORG",
            "Paragraph 3": "DATE",
            "Model\n      Law and Rules": "LAW",
            "3(5": "CARDINAL",
            "one": "CARDINAL",
            "66": "CARDINAL",
            "the Arbitration  Act": "LAW",
            "Arbitration Act": "LAW",
            "The Arbitration (Protocol and Convention": "ORG",
            "the Foreign Awards": "ORG",
            "Section 85": "LAW",
            "Earlier the 1937 Act": "TIME",
            "the Geneva Convention": "LAW",
            "1958": "DATE",
            "New  York\n      Convention": "GPE",
            "the Arbitration Act, 1996": "LAW",
            "Model Laws": "PRODUCT",
            "the New York Convention": "ORG"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "With  these  objects  in  view,  the  UNCITRAL   Model   Law   on\n      International Arbitration (“the Model Law”) was adopted by the  United\n      Nations Commission on International Trade Law (UNCITRAL) on 21st June,\n      1985 at the end of the 18th Session of the  Commission.",
            "The  General\n      Assembly in its      Resolution 40 of  1972  on  11th  December,  1985\n      recommended that \"all States give due consideration to the  Model  Law\n      on international commercial arbitration, in view of  the  desirability\n      of uniformity of the law of arbitral procedures and the specific needs\n      of international commercial arbitration practice\".",
            "Does the missing ‘only’ indicate a deviation from Article 1(2) of  the\n      Model Law?\n       64.",
            "As noticed earlier the objects and reasons for  the  enactment  of\n      the Arbitration Act, 1996 clearly indicate  that  the  Parliament  had\n      taken into account the UNCITRAL Model  Laws.",
            "The  statement  of  the\n      objects and reasons of the Arbitration  Act,  1996  clearly  indicates\n      that law of arbitration in India at  the  time  of  enactment  of  the\n      Arbitration  Act,  1996,  was   substantially   contained   in   three\n      enactments,  namely,  The  Arbitration  Act,  1940;  The   Arbitration\n      (Protocol  and  Convention)  Act,  1937   and   The   Foreign   Awards\n      (Recognition and Enforcement) Act, 1961.",
            "It is  specifically  observed\n      that it is widely felt that the Arbitration Act, 1940, which  contains\n      the general law of arbitration, has become outdated.",
            "It also mentions\n      that the Law Commission of India,  several  representative  bodies  of\n      trade and industry and experts  in  the  fields  of  arbitration  have\n      proposed amendments to the Arbitration Act,  1940,  to  make  it  more\n      responsive to contemporary requirements.",
            "It was also recognized  that\n      the economic reforms initiated by India at that time  may  not  become\n      fully effective, if the law dealing with settlement of  both  domestic\n      and international commercial dispute remained out of  tune  with  such\n      reforms.",
            "The objects and reasons  further  make  it  clear  that  the\n      general  assembly  has  recommended  that  all  countries   give   due\n      consideration to the Model Law adopted in 1985, by  the  UNCITRAL,  in\n      view of  the  desirability  of  uniformity  of  the  law  of  arbitral\n      procedures  and  the  specific  needs  of   international   commercial\n      arbitration practice.",
            "Paragraph 3 of the statement  of  objects  and\n      reasons makes it clear that  although  the  UNCITRAL  Model  Laws  are\n      intended  to  deal  with  international  commercial  arbitration   and\n      conciliation, they could, with appropriate modifications, serve  as  a\n      Model Law for legislation of domestic  arbitration  and  conciliation.",
            "Therefore, the bill was introduced seeking to  consolidate  and  amend\n      the law relating to  domestic  arbitration,  international  commercial\n      arbitration, enforcement of foreign arbitral award and to  define  the\n      law relating to conciliation, taking into account the  UNCITRAL  Model\n      Law and Rules.",
            "Whilst interpreting the provisions of the Arbitration  Act,  1996,\n      it is necessary to remember that we are dealing  with  the  Act  which\n      seeks  to  consolidate  and  amend  the  law  relating   to   domestic\n      arbitration, international commercial arbitration and  enforcement  of\n      foreign arbitral awards.",
            "The aforesaid Act also seeks to  define  the\n      law relating to conciliation and for matters  connected  therewith  or\n      incidental thereto.",
            "The\n      domestic  law  of  arbitration  had  remained   static   since   1940.",
            "Therefore, the Arbitration Act, 1996 consolidates the law on  domestic\n      arbitrations by incorporating the provisions to  expressly  deal  with\n      the domestic as  well  as  international  commercial  arbitration;  by\n      taking into account the 1985 UNCITRAL Model Laws.",
            "It is also necessary to  appreciate  that\n      the Arbitration Act, 1996 seeks to remove the anomalies  that  existed\n      in the Arbitration Act, 1940 by introducing provisions  based  on  the\n      UNCITRAL  Model  Laws,  which  deals  with  international   commercial\n      arbitrations and also extends it to commercial domestic  arbitrations.",
            "UNCITRAL  Model  Law  has  unequivocally  accepted   the   territorial\n      principle."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/173015163/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "47.     The   Preamble   of   the   Arbitration   and   Conciliation   Act,   1996   is   as \n\n\nfollows:\n \n...",
        "Entities": {
            "47": "CARDINAL",
            "Arbitration": "EVENT",
            "1996": "DATE"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": "No key legal principles provided.",
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/1851595/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "14.   In view of the definition of `goods' it became vital to correctly\nunderstand the nature and attributes of moveable property. The Sales\nTax Acts had no definition of the expression and the meaning given\nin the General Clauses Acts of the three States was also found to be\nnot of much help. The c...",
        "Entities": {
            "14": "CARDINAL",
            "the General Clauses Acts": "ORG",
            "three": "CARDINAL",
            "States": "GPE",
            "Black's Law Dictionary": "LAW",
            "6th": "ORDINAL",
            "1990": "DATE",
            "A.H. Hudson": "PERSON",
            "Butterworths": "PERSON",
            "1983": "DATE",
            "Jowitt": "ORG",
            "Dictionary of English Law (Sweet": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "Maxwell Limited": "ORG",
            "1977": "DATE",
            "Chapter 13": "LAW",
            "The Law of Property": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "Salmond": "PERSON",
            "Jurisprudence": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "23": "CARDINAL",
            "Anjar": "GPE",
            "Court": "ORG",
            "35": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "It referred to\nBlack's Law Dictionary (6th.",
            "Edn. 1990), Dictionary of Commercial\nLaw by A.H. Hudson (published by Butterworths, 1983) and Jowitt's\nDictionary of English Law (Sweet and Maxwell Limited, 1977) and\nnoted that all the commentaries and the referred case law uniformly\nemphasised the expansive manner in which the expression `property'\nwas understood.",
            "The court also referred to the meanings of the term\n`property' set out in Chapter 13, \"The Law of Property\" in Salmond's\nJurisprudence (12th."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/929151/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "\n 9.    The general principle that we have accepted is supported by two passages\n\nin Comparative International Commercial Arbitration.2 In paragraph 24-3\n\nthereof reference is made to Article 31(1) of the United Nations Commission on\n\nInternational Trade Law (or UNCITRAL) Rules to suggest that while...",
        "Entities": {
            "9": "CARDINAL",
            "two": "CARDINAL",
            "Comparative International Commercial": "EVENT",
            "24-3": "CARDINAL",
            "Article 31(1": "LAW",
            "the United Nations Commission on\n\nInternational Trade Law": "ORG",
            "Chapter 24": "LAW",
            "Loukas A. Mistelis": "PERSON",
            "al.": "GPE",
            "Comparative International Commercial Arbitration": "ORG",
            "Kluwer Law International": "ORG",
            "Kluwer\nLaw International 2003": "ORG",
            "627 - 662": "CARDINAL",
            "C.A. Nos.2562": "ORG",
            "2006": "DATE",
            "6": "CARDINAL",
            "24-13": "DATE",
            "11": "CARDINAL",
            "Paragraph 1353": "DATE",
            "28": "CARDINAL",
            "second": "ORDINAL",
            "Section 34": "LAW",
            "the A&C Act": "LAW",
            "Page 17": "FAC",
            "16": "CARDINAL",
            "Article 34(1": "LAW"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "In paragraph 24-3\n\nthereof reference is made to Article 31(1) of the United Nations Commission on\n\nInternational Trade Law (or UNCITRAL) Rules to suggest that while all awards\n\nare decisions of the arbitral tribunal, all decisions of the arbitral tribunal are not\n\nawards.",
            "The distinction between an award and a decision of an arbitral\n\n\n2 Chapter 24 Arbitration Award in Julian D. M. Lew, Loukas A. Mistelis, et al.,\nComparative International Commercial Arbitration, (© Kluwer Law International; Kluwer\nLaw International 2003) pp.",
            "In this context, the view\n\nexpressed in the Analytical Commentary On Draft Text of A Model Law on\n\nInternational Commercial Arbitration - Report of the Secretary-General 16 is\n\nquite relevant.",
            "This commentary deals, inter alia, with Article 34(1) of the Model\n\nLaw on International Commercial Arbitration17 and it is stated as follows:"
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/114255072/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "     (ii) in the case of international commercial\n           arbitration, the High Court in exercise of its\n           ordinary original civil jurisdiction, having\n           jurisdiction to decide the questions forming the\n           subject matter of the arbitration if the same\n           had been...",
        "Entities": {
            "the High Court": "ORG",
            "High Court": "ORG",
            "India": "GPE",
            "at least one": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "(ii) in the case of international commercial\n           arbitration, the High Court in exercise of its\n           ordinary original civil jurisdiction, having\n           jurisdiction to decide the questions forming the\n           subject matter of the arbitration if the same\n           had been the subject matter of a suit, and in\n           other cases, a High Court having jurisdiction\n           to hear appeals from decrees of courts\n           subordinate to that High Court;\n (f) “international commercial arbitration” means an\n     arbitration relating to disputes arising out of legal\n     relationships, whether contractual or not, considered\n     as commercial under the law in force in India and\n     where at least one of the parties is—"
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/79928496/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "Take notes as you read a judgment using our Virtual Legal Assistant and get email alerts whenever a new judgment matches your query (Query Alert Service). Try out our Premium Member Services -- Sign up today and get free trial for one month.  1. Under section 256(1) of the Income-tax Act, 1961, at t...",
        "Entities": {
            "Virtual Legal": "ORG",
            "Premium Member Services": "ORG",
            "today": "DATE",
            "one month": "DATE",
            "1.": "CARDINAL",
            "section 256(1": "LAW",
            "1961": "DATE",
            "Madras-II": "LOC",
            "Madras": "LOC",
            "Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "2": "CARDINAL",
            "65 per cent": "MONEY",
            "Appellate": "ORG",
            "the Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Tribunal": "ORG",
            "55 per cent": "MONEY",
            "the Finance Act": "LAW",
            "1968": "DATE",
            "3": "CARDINAL",
            "Section 2(6)(d": "LAW",
            "4": "CARDINAL",
            "5": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": "No key legal principles provided.",
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/623546/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": " There is no dispute that United Kingdom is one of the countries which has been notified.  The definition of 'foreign award' will show that in order to fall within that definition. the award must satisfy certain requirements.  Firstly, it must be an award on differences between persons who have lega...",
        "Entities": {
            "United Kingdom": "GPE",
            "Firstly": "ORDINAL",
            "secondly": "ORDINAL",
            "India": "GPE",
            "thirdly": "ORDINAL",
            "11th": "ORDINAL",
            "Oct. 1960": "DATE",
            "the New York Convention": "ORG",
            "State": "ORG",
            "Parliament": "ORG",
            "18": "CARDINAL",
            "Nariman": "PERSON",
            "Counsel": "ORG",
            "Indian Organic Chemicals Ltd.'s": "ORG",
            "24": "CARDINAL",
            "1961": "DATE",
            "The New York  Convention": "ORG",
            "New York": "GPE",
            "the  1961 Act": "TIME",
            "Indian Organic chemicals Ltd.'s": "ORG",
            "41:--": "CARDINAL"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "and secondly, the legal relationship must be considered as commercial under the law in force in India, and thirdly, the award must be made on or after 11th Oct. 1960 and lastly, the award must be in pursuance of an agreement in writing for arbitration to which the New York Convention applies.",
            "The definition will show that when it referred to \"legal relationship ............. considered as commercial under the law in force in India\".",
            "it was intended to give effect to the declaration in the Convention that the legal relationship must be considered as commercial under the national law of the State making the declaration and in terms of the accession of India to the New York Convention.",
            "The declaration was that the legal relationship, whether contractual or not, was to be such as is considered as commercial under the law of India.",
            "Therefore, when the Parliament used the words \"law in force in India,\" we cannot lose sight of the fact that the use of those words was intended to give effect to the concept of  'law of India' contained in the declaration of accession and to the concept 'national law of the State making a declaration.'",
            "Mr. Nariman appearing on behalf of the appellants has contended that when the definition of foreign award uses the phraseology \"considered as commercial under the law in force in India,\" it has merely to be ascertained whether a legal relationship is regarded by law as commercial or whether a legal relationship is recognised in law as commercial and, according to the learned Counsel, it was not necessary to enact any particular statute, as seems to be contemplated by the decision in Indian Organic Chemicals Ltd.'s case  which would specify or indicate what legal  relationships were to be commercial for the purposes of the 1961 Act.",
            "the contention is that if under the general law of the land, a particular relationship was considered as commercial in the normal sense of the term.",
            "Now, when the definition of foreign award  refers to \"legal relationships ............... considered  as commercial under the law in force in India:\" we cannot overlook the fact that the 1961  Act was intended to give effect to the New York Convention.",
            "The New York  Convention mad reference to the national law and the deceleration of accession to the New York convention by India made reference  to the law of  India,  Now.",
            "the words \"national law\"  or \"the law of  India\" no  doubt will  take in a particular  statute,  but these  worse Arbitration of such wide import that they will  envelope the entire body of law which are effective or operative  in India.",
            "Indeed when the statute uses the words \"law in force  in  India\"  such use of words could never have contemplated a reference to any particular law and while it may in a given case in the context refer to a law on that particular subject, generally such words  are used  when reference is made to the general body of laws  operative  in India.",
            "We have repeatedly asked  the learned Counsel for the  intervene and the respondent as to what kind of provision they contemplate which they argued that there has to be a law which deals with contractual legal relationships and declares them to be commercial.",
            "With   several kinds of transactions which may be considered as commercial on the facts of each case, it is obvious that when the parliament referred  to the legal relationships considered as commercial under the  law in force in India.",
            "it  had in mind the general body of laws with reference to which the nature of the transaction would be considered.",
            "The  nature of the relationships will depend   in the nature of the transaction and whether the nature of the  transaction is commercial or not will have  to be determined with reference generally to the law  in force in the country  inclusive of what  the learned Judge, who decided the Indian Organic chemicals Ltd.'s case  referred to as an operative legal principle  in force in India.",
            "The mean  use of the words 'under preceding  the words  \"law in force in India\"  would not, in our view, necessarily mean that you  have to find a statutory provision or a provision of law which specifically deals with the subject of particular legal relationships being commercial in  nature.",
            "The proposition laid down by the learned Judge cannot be disputed, However,  when the learned Judge  proceeding to construe the provision in S. 2 of the 1916 Act the emphasised the use of the words \"under the law in force in India\" and then observed  as follows in para 41:--"
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/15960/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "      From more than one point of view, there is, in our view, no doubt\nthat, constitutionally, Parliament can make a law under Entry 78 of List I\nread with Entry 11A of List III of the Seventh Schedule to the Constitution\ncreating a separate division as 'Commercial Division' in the High Court and\np...",
        "Entities": {
            "more than one": "CARDINAL",
            "Parliament": "ORG",
            "Entry 78 of List": "LAW",
            "Constitution": "LAW",
            "the High Court": "ORG",
            "Division Bench": "PERSON",
            "Rs.1": "CARDINAL",
            "Division": "ORG",
            "Art": "PERSON",
            "224A": "CARDINAL",
            "the Constitution of India": "ORG",
            "High Court": "ORG",
            "the 'Commercial Division'": "ORG",
            "Chapters": "NORP",
            "Commercial Division": "ORG",
            "Chapter IX": "LAW",
            "Chapter VI": "LAW",
            "Commercial Divisions": "ORG",
            "UK": "GPE",
            "USA": "GPE",
            "The Law Commission": "ORG",
            "1996": "DATE",
            "India": "GPE",
            "Commercial": "ORG",
            "chapter VII": "LAW",
            "Commercial\nCourt Guide'": "ORG",
            "the Commercial Courts": "ORG",
            "England": "GPE",
            "Commercial Court": "ORG",
            "Theobald Matthew's": "PERSON",
            "the Commercial Court": "ORG",
            "Scrutton": "PERSON",
            "'The Work of the Commercial Courts'": "WORK_OF_ART",
            "1923": "DATE",
            "1": "CARDINAL",
            "Journal": "ORG",
            "6": "CARDINAL",
            "Practice Directions": "ORG",
            "5th Ed": "PERSON",
            "1999": "DATE",
            "Admiralty and Commercial Court Guide'": "ORG",
            "Ed": "PERSON",
            "Feb. 2002": "DATE",
            "Guide": "ORG",
            "58": "CARDINAL",
            "61": "DATE",
            "62": "CARDINAL",
            "the Civil Procedure Rules": "ORG",
            "Admiralty Proceedings": "PERSON",
            "49": "CARDINAL",
            "5th": "ORDINAL",
            "the Commercial Court Guide": "ORG",
            "the Admiralty and Commercial Courts": "FAC",
            "2": "CARDINAL",
            "NUTSHELL": "ORG"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "From more than one point of view, there is, in our view, no doubt\nthat, constitutionally, Parliament can make a law under Entry 78 of List I\nread with Entry 11A of List III of the Seventh Schedule to the Constitution\ncreating a separate division as 'Commercial Division' in the High Court and\nprescribe pecuniary limits for pending and new cases of (say) Rs.1 crore or\nabove on the original side with 'fast track' procedure and also permit the\nseparate Division Bench to deal with pending appeals in the High Court,\nbelonging to the pecuniary jurisdiction of (say) Rs.1 crore (or such higher\nfigure as may be fixed by the High Court) and to enable the Chief Justice of\nthe High Court to nominate Judges of the High Court to that Division from\ntime to time.",
            "If there are Judges who have retired and have exceptional\nknowledge of commercial laws, they can be appointed in the same or any\nother High Court and nominated to the 'Commercial Division'.",
            "The Law Commission, in its 176th Report on Amendments to\nthe Indian Arbitration and Conciliation Act, 1996 proposed a 'fast-track'\nprocedure for arbitration in India, where parties opt for such a procedure.",
            "Cambridge Law Journal 6)."
        ],
        "URL": "https://indiankanoon.org/docfragment/185454903/?formInput=commercial%20law"
    },
    {
        "Title": "Commercial Law Case",
        "Summary": "          This Bill as well as the Arbitration and Conciliation (Amendment) Bill, 2015 are two of the important commercial legislations brought about by the Government with a view to providing ease of doing business in India.  \n           The Law Commission of India, headed by Chief Justice A.P. Sha...",
        "Entities": {
            "the Arbitration and Conciliation (Amendment) Bill": "ORG",
            "2015": "DATE",
            "two": "CARDINAL",
            "India": "GPE",
            "The Law Commission": "ORG",
            "A.P. Shah": "PERSON",
            "253rd Report": "ORG",
            "29th January, 2015": "DATE",
            "the Law Ministry": "ORG",
            "Commercial Disputes": "ORG",
            "the year 2015-16": "DATE",
            "The Union Law Ministry": "ORG",
            "the Rajya Sabha": "ORG",
            "the Monsoon Session": "LOC",
            "the Parliamentary Standing Committee": "ORG",
            "the All-India Judicial Services": "ORG",
            "the Indian Administrative Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Foreign Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Forest Service": "ORG",
            "Indian Police Service": "ORG",
            "the Tribunals like Competition Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "National Company Law Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Security Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "Appellate Tribunal": "ORG",
            "the Commercial Appellate Division of the High Court": "ORG",
            "Tribunals": "PRODUCT",
            "Section 2": "LAW",
            "Law Minister": "PERSON",
            "Law": "PERSON",
            "Schedule": "PERSON",
            "Bill": "PERSON"
        },
        "Key Legal Principles": [
            "The Law Commission of India, headed by Chief Justice A.P. Shah (Retd.), in its 253rd Report dated 29th January, 2015 submitted to the Law Ministry, proposed a new legislation to deal exclusively with Commercial Disputes.",
            "The Union Law Ministry introduced this Bill in the Rajya Sabha in the Monsoon Session which was referred to the Parliamentary Standing Committee.",
            "The commercial dispute has to be heard by experts with demonstrable expertise than those people having the commercial law because it is not the institution that we are creating.",
            "We have to evolve a transparent method of appointment of judges and appoint those judges having specialised knowledge in commercial law because we are in a globalised economy and specialisation in every subject is very necessary.",
            "Just like the Indian Administrative Service, Indian Foreign Service, Indian Forest Service, Indian Police Service, we can recruit the judges in commercial courts, especially, those who are having knowledge in commercial law.",
            "But if we are recruiting judges having knowledge of general law and not having specialised knowledge of commercial law, then the same situation will arise where it is not the system which would fail us but we will fail the system itself.",
